Life out of balance
Koyaanisqatsi is a documentary, music film directed by Godfrey Reggio.
Takes us to locations all around the US and shows us the heavy toll
that modern technology is having on humans and the earth.
The visual tone poem contains neither dialogue nor a vocalized narration: its tone is set
by the juxtaposition of images and the exceptional music by Philip Glass.
Koyaanisqatsi is a 1982 American non-narrative documentary film directed and produced by
Godfrey Reggio, featuring music by Philip Glass and cinematography by Ron Fricke.
Described as an "essay in images and sound on the state of American civilization", the film comprises a montage of stock
footage, slow motion, and time-lapse visuals of natural and urban environments across the United States.
Following its premieres at the Telluride and New York Film Festivals in
1982, it began a limited theatrical release the next year.
Produced on a budget of $2.5 million, the film grossed $3.2 million at the box
office, and was one of the highest-grossing documentaries of the 1980s.
The title comes from the Hopi word koyaanisqatsi, meaning "life out of balance".
It is the first film in the Qatsi trilogy, which was followed
by Powaqqatsi (1988) and Naqoyqatsi (2002).
The trilogy depicts different aspects of the relationship
between humans, nature and technology.
Koyaanisqatsi is the best known of the trilogy and is considered a cult film.
The film explores themes of human vs nature, technology,
civilization, social commentary, rural area.